JAMES FROST

Greensboro, NC 336 210-1008 jcfrosty64@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jcfrost

SUMMARY

Technical Sales Engineer on successful sales team. Extensive experience promoting sales of fixed access telecommunications products to a major North America service provider.

Team Contributor

Technical Advisor

Problem Solver

Customer Focused

 Customer Lab Demonstrations

Manufacturing Engineer that oversaw production and testing of high reliability undersea communications cable for the US Navy. Six years experience in undersea cable manufacture, cable design, fiber optic testing, and system integration.

■ Team Contributor

Sub-contractor Management Problem Solver

Project Scheduling & Planning Customer Focused

Focused on Product Quality

EXPERIENCE

Alcatel-Lucent Greensboro NC

1986-2015

(formally Lucent Technologies & AT&T Federal Systems)

Sales Engineer, North America Major Wireline Sales Team

2007-2015

Technical sales engineer on North America Major Accounts Wireline Sales Team. Assisted sales account executives with activities to promote sales of fixed access telecommunications products (FTTH/FTTN/xDSL/5ESS Switching) & application platforms (virtualized Session Border Controller application).

- Contributed as a team member on a high performing customer sales team that grew annual revenue from \$80M to \$180M over last 5 years.
- Created customized solutions and pricing proposals for telecom customers to meet their wireline access product needs.
- Involved with customer discussions on proposed 5ESS grooming processes, procedures and pricing.

Provided technical and business case support to direct customers for qualification, assessment and proposal of service provider solution opportunities for large capital equipment sales of Alcatel-Lucent's fixed wireline products. This included customer presentations, lab system demonstrations, engineered customer solutions and teamed with sales account executives to promote and close sales deals.

Technical Consultant, Global Commercial Markets Sales Team

1997-2006

Technical consultant supporting technical sales in North America Global Commercial Markets. Supported multiple major 5ESS wireline switching customers (mostly consisting of CLECs). Provided technical and business case support to direct customers for qualification, assessment and proposal of service provider solution opportunities for large capital equipment sales of 5ESS Switching Systems that included customer presentations, engineered customer solutions and teamed with sales account executives to promote and close sales deals.

- Served as the lead technical sales engineer for 5ESS central office switch product line for all tier 2 and tier 3 wireline service providers in the United States.
- Created customized solutions and pricing proposals for telecom customers to meet their wireline Class 5 switching product needs.

JAMES FROST PAGE 2 OF 2

icfrosty64@gmail.com

Member of Technical Staff, Cable Management Group

1991-1996

Bell Labs Member of Technical Staff supporting US Navy Undersea Cable Systems projects. Liaison between multiple sub-contractors & US NAVY to oversee manufacture, test and delivery of high reliability undersea cable for the US Navy UWS (fiber optic) & SOSUS (coaxial & multi-pair) undersea surveillance systems.

- Served as the UWS Cable Production Readiness Review (PRR) coordinator
- Monitored and worked with sub-contractor to resolve product quality issues
- Increased production rates through continuous improvement initiatives
- Worked with subcontractors to resolve manufacturing issues coordinated root cause analysis
- Coordinated projects/deliverables with suppliers, sub-contractors, system integration, and deployment groups

Member of Technical Staff, Resident Engineering Program

1986-1990

Field engineer in AT&T Resident Engineering program with the US Navy. Performed resident engineering assignments at multiple US Navy locations (foreign and domestic) that provided on-site engineering support and maintained optimal performance of AT&T Bell Labs designed and manufactured power, signal processing and communications equipment used to monitor and detect underwater threats in defense of the US and its allies.

EDUCATION

M.S. Industrial Technology, North Carolina A&T State University, Greensboro, North Carolina *B.S. Computer Engineering*, Clemson University, Clemson, South Carolina

Computer Skills: MS Office Suite (Excel/Outlook/PowerPoint/Project) | MS Visio | Salesforce

COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP

- First Baptist Church, Greensboro a team leader for meal preparation and delivery supporting Grace Community Church's weekly Wednesday Fellowship Meal (monthly)
- First Baptist Church, Greensboro Middle School Boys Basketball Assistant Coach
- Friends of Uwharrie volunteer
- Greensboro Mobile Meals Volunteer